Guide to the Edmund Poley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1680-1705; Series I; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Mar (Box 3, Folder 141-47)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Apr (Box 3, Folder 148-51)
  - Correspondence, 1704 May (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Jun (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Jul (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Aug (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Correspondence, 1704 Sep (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Jan (Box 3, Folder 157-58)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Feb (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Mar (Box 3, Folder 160-61)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Apr (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Correspondence, 1705 May (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Jun (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Aug (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Sep (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Correspondence, 1705 Oct (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Letter fragments, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 169)
- Related Papers, 1645-1707; Series II; 2; (3 boxes)
  - Appointment of Edmund Poley as Master of the Harriers to Prince Charles, 1645 Dec 10 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Appointment of Edmund Poley as Clerk of Privy Council, 1660 Jun 27 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - King's warrant for payment of £3,000 to Robert Long, 1671 Aug 31 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Exclusion of James, Duke of York, copy of bill, [1680]
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Box 6, folder 213
  - "A List of ye Lords who voted Guilty or not Guilty in Lord Stafford's Triall" [in the hand of Roland Tempest], 1680 Dec 7 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Accounts of the House of Brunswick- Lüneburg by Sir Gabriel Sylvius and M. Beckornes, 1680 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Princes of the Empire, Queries about (in French), [1681 Feb] (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Credential of the Sieur de Bourgonville, French envoy to Württemberg (copy in French in Poley's hand), 1682 Feb 4 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - "Relation concerning the choice of Sheriffs", 1682 Jun 27 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Magdeburg Votum (in German), 1682 Oct 2/12 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - "Relation exacte de ce qui passé à Bantam", [1682] (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Conolusium Collegÿ Electoralis (in Latin), 1682 Dec 12 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Allowance for Edmund Poley of £3 per day (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Memorial of Daniel Johann Cramprick (copy in French), 1683 Apr 7 (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Memorial of Spanish envoy in The Hague, le marquis Castel Moncayo, 1683 Nov 12 (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - "Memoire de Monsr le Comte d'Avaux, Ambassr Extraordinaire de France, presenté à Messieurs les Estats Generaux" (copy), 1683 Dec 29
    See: Box 6, folder 214
  - Memorial of Arnaut Van Citters, Dutch ambassador, to Charles II (copy in French), 1684 Feb 26 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Memorial of Thomas Chudleigh to the States General (copy in French), 1684 Mar 7/17 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Charles II: Answer to memorial of Arnaut Van Citters, 1684 Mar 25 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Memorial of Count Franz Sigismund Thun-Hohenstein to Charles II (copy in French), 1684 Jul 20/30 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Address of Daniel Cosnac to Louis XIV (in French), 1685 Jul 14 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - "Catalogue of the Nobility and Principal Gentry Said to be in Arms with the Prince of Orange & in Severall other Parts of England", [1688 Dec] (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Diplomatic credentials for Edmund Poley to the court of Savoy (in French), 1692 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Memorial of military supplies needed to undertake siege of Pinerolo (in Italian), [1692 Jul 28] (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Guarantee of treaty between two branches of the House of Brunswick- Lüneburg (in Latin), 1695 May 2 (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - Docket of letter, 1696 May 9/19 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Memorial of Comte de Mansfeld concerning neutrality of Italy (in French), [1696 Oct?] (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - Draft of articles of peace between France and Savoy (in Italian), [1696] (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - Draft of article of proposed peace in Italy (in Latin and French), 1696 Nov 20 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Answer of court of Vienna to proposed treaties of Westphalia and Nijmegen (in Latin), [1696] (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - List of letters to and from Savoy, [1696] (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Inscription for triumphal arch to honor Georg Ludwig, Elector of Hanover, and Wilhelm, Duke of Celle (in Latin), 1700
    See: Box 6, folder 215
  - Poems: "Consolation pour Messieurs de Villeroy et de Boufleur Marchaux de France," and "A Louis le Grand", [ca. 1700] (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Convention between the Queen of Great Britain and Elector and Duke of Brunswick-Lüneburg (in French), 1702 Jun 21 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Treaty with Brunswick-Lüneburg (in French), 1702 Jul 10 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Convention with Georg Ludwig, Duke of Brunswick-Lüneburg and Elector of Hanover (in French), 1702 Nov 16 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Convention with Georg Wilhelm, Duke of Celle (in French), 1702 Dec 15 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Inscription for a triumphal arch to honor Georg Wilhelm, Duke of Celle and Georg Ludwig, Elector of Hanover (in Latin), 1702
    See: Box 6, folder 216
  - Diplomatic credentials for Edmund Poley to the court of Hannover (in Latin), 1703 Jul 31 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Private cipher between Edmund Poley and the Secretary of State (photocopy), 1702 Nov 2 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - "Treaty with the House of Lunebourg for 10,000 Men" (in French), 1703 Dec 13/24 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Memorandum of Pietro Mellarède concerning French intentions in Savoy (in French), 1704 Apr
    See: Box 6, folder 217
  - List of French officers taken prisoner at Blenheim (in the hand of Adam Cardonnel), 1704 Aug (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - List of French officers taken prisoner at Blenheim (in French, in Poley's hand), 1704 Aug (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - List of killed and wounded Lüneburg troops at Battle of Hochstadt, 1704 Aug (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - List of English officers killed and wounded at Batttle of Hochstadt, 1704 Aug
    See: Oversize, Box 6, folder 218
  - Poem: "Sur l'Air du Branlle de Mets", 1704 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Credentials of Edmund Poley from Elector of Hanover, 1705 Sep 14 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Settlement of estate of Henry Poley, 1707 Aug 27
    See: Box 6, folder 219
  - "Cypher between Earl of Nottingham and Mr. Poley"
    See: Box 6, folder 220
  - "A List of Mr. Poley's Dispatches", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Oversize
    - Exclusion of James (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - "Memoire... d'Avaux" (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Inscription (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Inscription (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - Memorandum of Pietro Mellarède (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - List of killed (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - Settlement of estate (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - "Cypher" (Box 6, Folder 220)